<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tales of a coder]]></title>
  <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-03T10:57:23+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matteo Manzo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graduated!]]></title>
    <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/03/22/graduated/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T17:35:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/03/22/graduated</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What a journey! I just graduated from Makers Academy after a 2 weeks final project, which it was totally crazy!!
At the beginning of the course I could have never imagined that with no experience before the course, I was able, with a team of other 4 makers (<a href="https://github.com/andygnewman">Andy</a>, <a href="https://github.com/marcinwal">Marcin</a>, <a href="https://github.com/jackrubio26">Jack</a> and <a href="https://github.com/hannahcarney">Hannah</a>) to build a fully working application, <a href="https://turnuptunein.herokuapp.com">TurnUp TuneIn</a> which lets you to organize your party playlist on Spotify and allow your friends to contribute to it!
<a href="https://github.com/matteomanzo/playlister">Check it out</a> to read more..
Makers was great, very hard to leave. In fact, I am still there everyday, working on my projects and getting as much support as I want in order to find the best companies to work with and the most useful resources to help me keep growing as I did during this 12 weeks.
That&rsquo;s pretty much it actually, I realised that I can not type the feelings and sensations that I feel right now, it feels strange, I feel great, but there is something going on that I never felt before and I am enjoying it.
I&rsquo;m off doing some work now and getting ready for the real world, after this incredibly powerful launching pad, I am building my path to become a great full-stack developer.</p>

<p>&hellip;wanna see the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vVipQomTmZY&amp;feature=youtu.be">presentation</a>?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makerthon]]></title>
    <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/03/17/makerthon/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-17T09:20:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/03/17/makerthon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a few weeks spent on new things (as usual here at Makers) we found ourselves building a small but working project in a team of 5 people, with a deadline of 3 days..
After deciding to build a game (just because it&rsquo;s fun, and obviously we didn&rsquo;t do it before) me, <a href="https://github.com/jackrubio26">Jack</a>, <a href="https://github.com/hannahcarney">Hannah</a>, <a href="https://github.com/indiadearlove">India</a> and <a href="https://github.com/ciawalsh">Charlie</a>, started to think about designing the game..
We came out with a character in a room, where a massive iron ball bounces around and the only way to survive, of course, is avoiding the ball or you&rsquo;ll be crushed.
Once we had the minimum value product in our mind, we looked for the technology to use.. from somewhere, we could here the whispers.. &ldquo;JavaScript&hellip;.&rdquo;, &ldquo;JavaScript&hellip;.&rdquo;&hellip; Right!
Javascript was a great choice, we didn&rsquo;t know anything about C++ and also we could find a few packages that could help us managing the game physics and animation. After the whole morning spent thinking of how to implement our MVP, we came across <a href="https://www.phaser.io">Phaser</a>, an HTML5 game framework (check it out, it&rsquo;s free and very very cool) with some built-in methods, &lsquo;easy&rsquo; to use and lots of fun.
After the first day, we had the game MVP working: One character, one ball. When they touch, the character dies.
Something was missing though, we knew that we had to add a lot of features and we didn&rsquo;t have enough time in 3 days, so we decided to bring two new features: beat the highscore and multiple balls!
The game was starting to having a shape, and we were starting to have some conflicts about priorities, some of us wanted to have a better user experience making the physics more realistic, some others wanted to make the game looks nicer.. It wasn&rsquo;t easy to manage the stress, but at the end we managed to find the balance again and focus on something very unusual&hellip;
The room became a garden, the character became a farmer, and the balls.. Became zombie pigs!! Bhuahahaha..!!!
Now, the first thought that you&rsquo;ll have when you will click on <a href="https://zombie-pig-pong.herokuapp.com">THIS LINK</a> will be: &ldquo;Wow, this game needs some work!&rdquo;, so that&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m asking you to contribute to my repo on <a href="https://github.com/matteomanzo/PigPong">GitHub</a> and help us make it better.. We are proud of what we&rsquo;ve done in such a short period and at the same time we believe that the beautiful community of developers out there will give us a hand to make it better..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn by doing..]]></title>
    <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/makers-academy/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T07:46:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/makers-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learn by doing it&rsquo;s our motto at Makers Academy!
For those who might ask what Makers Academy is.. Well, in the first instance I would say that it&rsquo;s a 12 weeks full immersive web development course where, starting from scratch, you learn how to build a web application in different programming languages, using an impressive variety of tools like databases, frameworks, APIs, etc.. To create real projects all together.
Technically this is correct, but it&rsquo;s not all!
As Sam, our Head of Education, always said at the beginning: &ldquo;this won&rsquo;t be just a technical journey, in fact, it will be more an EMOTIONAL journey..&rdquo; and I totally agree with him.
The best way to consolidate your knowledge is to teach, the best way to learn.. It&rsquo;s learning together! I&rsquo;ll come back to this point in few paragraphs..
Before I started the course I was only able to play games with the computer, write documents, send emails and crash most of the stuff that was in my laptop. So I was quite scared on the first day of the pre-course, (which is an incredibly useful part of the course, structured in four weeks to help you being confident with the tools that will become your fork and knife, like the command-line, git..) but soon I&rsquo;ve started to enjoy typing in that black box and writing VERY easy programs in Ruby, like printing the string &ldquo;Hello World!&rdquo; or even make very sophisticated calcs like &ldquo;2 + (3 * 4)&rdquo; and see the result printend on my terminal&hellip;
Then, suddenly, the first day of the real course has arrived..
Everyone looked scary and nervous, but after one hour of introducing ourselves, a few chats and setting ourselves comfortable, we started to pair program.. And I understood the magic.
I was pairing with Jacob, trying to recreate the Boris Bikes system, and we had such an amount of issues in the program and in the machine (we learnt a lot by deleting very important files from the laptop, but I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend it to anyone, and neither do Jacob) that we started laughing and try to co-operate to fix as many issues as we could, and it was lots of fun!
If you program by yourself you will learn not even half of the things that you will learn if you pair with someone, and that someone it could be anyone! Yes, because even if your partner has less experience than you, he will try to learn the things that he doesn&rsquo;t know, and you will be explaining
him things that you already know (or you think you knew) and you might find out that you had some lacks.. So you&rsquo;re learning together.
Makers it&rsquo;s all about this, that&rsquo;s why it&rsquo;s emotional. You pair with different people every week or even every day, and it&rsquo;s great! I love teamwork, and I love stay with people, and I&rsquo;ve got the feeling that these guys who I&rsquo;m working with are not anymore classmates or coaches or assistants, but we all starting to be good friends, like a big family!</p>

<p>Now it&rsquo;s time to do some coding, but if you didn&rsquo;t put my blog on the trash yet, then check it again in the next days because I will be writing more about the journey..</p>

<p>See you soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's alive!]]></title>
    <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/it-is-alive/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T00:10:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/it-is-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a long and winding road, but I&rsquo;m online!! Probably you&rsquo;re not so excited as I am but, trust me, working on this blog for 5 weeks, 5 WEEKS, error by error trying to figure out how to set it up properly it hasn&rsquo;t be easy (especially when your friend next to you does the same exact thing in about 25 minutes without an error..) but anyway&hellip;.
There are some changes in the air!! First of all, I&rsquo;m writing a blog!  Never done anything like that before!! (I guess I know why now..)<br/>
I never understood why people would write a blog, it always sounded creepy to me that all these attention-seeking people who wanted just some feedback are filling pages after pages with they&rsquo;re holidays adventures or, even worst, tips for a better life.. But I&rsquo;ve changed my mind..
&ldquo;Why am I doing it then?&rdquo; Basically because I want to keep track of the things that I will be doing from now on, stay connected with people, and because it will be fun in two years to read what I am writing now..
Anyhow, apparently  writing a blog is not the biggest change that is going on.
A few things are happening.. So let&rsquo;s start with the first one then, because I&rsquo;m on my way to become a Maker&hellip;.</p>

<p>PS: As you can see from the subtitle this blog it&rsquo;s not just about the syntax and so I apologise in advance for all the spelling errors that I&rsquo;ll do, I&rsquo;ll try my best and I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll appreciate the effort&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
