<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tales of a coder]]></title>
  <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-22T00:10:56+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matteo Manzo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[it's alive!]]></title>
    <link href="http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/it-is-alive/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T00:10:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://matteomanzo.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/it-is-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a long and winding road, but I&rsquo;m online!! Probably you&rsquo;re not so excited as I am but, trust me, working on this blog for 5 weeks, 5 WEEKS, error by error trying to figure out how to set it up properly it hasn&rsquo;t be easy (especially when your friend next to you does the same exact thing in about 25 minutes without an error..) but anyway&hellip;.
There are some changes in the air!! First of all, I&rsquo;m writing a blog!  Never done anything like that before!! (I guess I know why now..)<br/>
I never understood why people would write a blog, it always sounded creepy to me that all these attention-seeking people who wanted just some feedback are filling pages after pages with they&rsquo;re holidays adventures or, even worst, tips for a better life.. But I&rsquo;ve changed my mind..
&ldquo;Why am I doing it then?&rdquo; Basically because I want to keep track of the things that I will be doing from now on, stay connected with people, and because it will be fun in two years to read what I am writing now..
Anyhow, apparently  writing a blog is not the biggest change that is going on.
A few things are happening.. So let&rsquo;s start with the first one then, because I&rsquo;m on my way to become a Maker&hellip;.</p>

<p>PS: As you can see from the subtitle this blog it&rsquo;s not just about the syntax and so I apologise in advance for all the spelling errors that I&rsquo;ll do, I&rsquo;ll try my best and I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll appreciate the effort&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
